Anne Hampton Brewster papers LCP.Brewster
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series II. Diaries and journals
  - Journal, 1845 June-1848 December (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal with poem fragment, 1849 January-1851 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1855 August-1858 April (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1858 April-1859 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Journal with envelopes and mementos, 1859 January-1860 September (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1860 October-1862 April (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1862 May-1865 May (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1865 May-1867 July (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journal (with trading card with calendar and manuscript fragment) 1867 August-1871 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1868-1892 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Journal Fragment, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1871 October-1874 April (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Journal with visiting card and note from Mrs. Charles D. Warner, 1874 April-1877 November (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Journal with pencil drawing of house with plans, 1877 February-1877 November (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Journal with Illustrated Easter card, visiting cards, and French holy card, 1877 December-1882 October (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1882 October-1885 October (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1885 October-1886 September (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1886 September-1888 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1888 February-1888 December (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1889 September-1890 July (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1890 July-1891 September (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1891 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1891 September-1892 March (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series III. Commonplace books
  - Fragment, [1845?]-1854 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1846, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1850-1851 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Poetry, 1850-1851 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - French idiom book and everyday readings, 1850-1858 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Everyday readings, 1851-1855 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1855-1857 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notebook (with newspaper clipping of article, "Metternich-A Retrospect"), 1857-1861 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1857-1861 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1858-1869 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - With sheet music, 1860-1862 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1861-1867 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1861-1874 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1862-1864 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1863-1864 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, 1864-1865 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1865 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1867-1869 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1867-1885 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue of library, 1868-1869 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1869 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - With Croix des Catacombes de Saint-Pontien a Rome pamphlet, 1869-1870 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1870 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1870 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1870-1871 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1871 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1871 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - With Episcopal church building fund donation form and notes, 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1871-1877 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1872-1873 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - With newspaper clipping "On batit actuellement dans le jardin de l'hôpital", 1873 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - With newspaper clippings, 1873-1874 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - With newspaper clipping "A Ostia sono state scoperte in questi", 1874 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - With newspaper clippings, 1874 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1874-1875 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1875 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - With newspaper clippings, 1875-1876 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1875 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1875 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1875-1876 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1875, 1877, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - With newspaper clippings, tonic directions, and a stamp, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1876-1877 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1877 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1877-1878 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1878 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1878-1879 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1879 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1879 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1879-1880 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1880 February (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1880 May (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1880 August (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1880-1881 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1880-1887 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1881 January (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1881 April (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1881 August (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Everyday readings, 1881-1882 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1882-1883 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1883 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1883-1884 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1884-1885 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1885 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1885-1886 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1887-1890 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1889-1890 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1890-1892 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Fragment, 1892 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Address book, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Copybooks
  - Abstracts of newsletters, 1869 October 12-1870 June 21 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Blackwoods Magazine (including "Miss Cushman" and "Washington in 1846. Leaves from a Young Woman's Journal"), 1878 August (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser (fragment), 1870 May 6 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1870 July-1871 May (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1871 June-1872 September (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1872 December-1874 September (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser (with letter from Brewster to Goddard), 1874 October-1876 January (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1876 February-1877 July (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1877 August-1878 September (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1878 October-1879 October (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1879 November-1880 July (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1880 September-1881 September (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser and Daily Evening Telegraph, 1881 October-1882 September (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1882 October-1883 March (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Boston Daily Advertiser, 1883 April-June (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Boston Sunday Herald, 1887 January-April (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Boston Sunday Herald, 1887 April-June (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Boston Sunday Herald, 1887 September-December (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Boston Sunday Herald, 1888 January 1 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1885 May-December (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1886 January-August (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1886 September-1887 May (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1887 June-1888 January (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Cincinnati Commercial (with letter from Brewster to Murat Halstead 1871 February 14), 1870 August-1871 February (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Cincinnati Gazette, 1873 May 10 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Continental, 1880 October 23 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1878 July-November (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1878 December-1879 April (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1879 April-August (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1879 August-1880 January (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1880 February-June (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1880 June-November (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1880 November-1881 March (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia) (with correspondence from Brewster to Editor, Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia) 1881 April 13), 1881 March-July (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1881 July-December (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Daily Evening Telegraph (Philadelphia), 1881 December-1882 January (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Lippincott's Magazine, 1844? (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Lippincott's Magazine, 1844? (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - New Century (with letter from Brewster to Editor, New York Graphic), 1876 July, 1876 September 2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - New York Evening Post ("What is Doing and Has Been done in Rome"), 1885 February, 1886 December, 1887 February (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - New York World (with review of Daniel Deronda by George Eliot, the Boston Advertiser, and The Philadelphia Evening Bulletin), 1876 August-1877 February (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - New York World, 1876 August-1877 April (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - New York World, 1877 December-1878 June (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - New York World, 1878 April-June (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Newark Courier (fragment), 1870 June 6 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Newark Courier (with Cincinnati Commercial and Philadelphia Evening Bulletin), 1870 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Newark Courier, 1870 August-November (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Newark Courier, 1870 November 15-29 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Newark Courier (fragment) (with "Occupations of Romans not used), undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Parisian, 1879 November-1880 March (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Parisian ("Le Contrade of Siena"), 1880 March-April (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1870 July-November (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1870 November-1871 March (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1871 March-September (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1871 September-1872 February (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin (with Boston Advertiser), 1872 March-October (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1872 October-1873 May (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1873 May-August (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1873 August-November (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1873 November-1874 May (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1874 May-October (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1874 November-1875 May (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1875 May-November (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1875 November-1876 April (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1876 May-November (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1876 November-1877 April (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1877 May-October (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1877 October-1878 February (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1878 March-June (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1885 March-June (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, 1885 June-September (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Series V. Drafts of articles, literature and nonfiction
  - Fiction: Chapter 2. Father and Daughter, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Fiction: Chapter 3d. Little Threads, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Fiction: "Elysium" from Saint Martin's Summer, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Fiction: "Franz and Leonard", undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Fiction: "Life's Reaping", undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Fiction: "The Magic Gater of the Villa Palombara at Rome", undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Fiction: "The New Model", undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles, drafts, 1870s-1880s (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Nonfiction: Christina of Sweden, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Nonfiction: "Corilla Olimpica", undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Nonfiction: "French Chateau Life", circa 1884 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Nonfiction: "Longfellow", undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Nonfiction: "Mariano Fortuny", circa 1875 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Nonfiction: Memoirs-childhood recollections-family history, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Nonfiction: Memoirs-recollection of voyage to Europe in 1868, 1868 September 9 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Nonfiction: "Music in Naples, Matteo, and Ducci", undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Nonfiction: "On European Cities", undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Nonfiction: On the Coronation Ceremony of King Charles Emmanuel III, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Nonfiction: "A Poet's Crowning", undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Nonfiction: "Procession of the St. Francesca Romana Relics" from the Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, Letter no. 13, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Nonfiction: "Professor Cesare Maccari" (with Maccari's visiting card), undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Nonfiction: "A Roman Marriage a Hundred Years Ago", undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Nonfiction: "The Story of Beefsteak" (fragment), undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Nonfiction: "Streets of Rome", undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Nonfiction: "Was His Majesty Mad?", undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Nonfiction: "Washington Forty Years Ago" (Female Society in Washington, D. C. 1846-1850), undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Poetry: "I have seen a young girl" (first line), undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Translations: "The First Wrinkle" (translation from French), 1889 May 25 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Translations: "Historical Compendium of the Palatine" by Lanciani and Visconti, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, 1869, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, 1869, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous personal papers and ephemera
  - Accademia Drammatic-Musicale, La Sigra Adelaide Ristori program, 1871 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "Anne Hathaway" (poem), undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Arcadia certificate of membership for Anne Hampton Brewster (with envelope), 1873 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "Bessie" (printed poem, two copies), 1888 December (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "Biblioteca Degli Arcadi", 1882 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Bookmark from Brewster's commonplace book: Poems 1850, circa 1850 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - "Carta Della Spedizione Francese in Tunisia," map, circa 1881 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Personal visiting cards, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - List of books, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - List of "Home Works of Reference", undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Typescript fragment regarding Benjamin Harris Brewster, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - "Copy of a Prayer Found in an Old English Paper", undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "Edwina and Dorothy" (printed poem), 1888 December 9 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - "February Magazines" (mentions Brewster's "Palimpsest of Paris"), undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Grand Hotel de Perugia menu, circa 1880s (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - "Great Weakness I Prove" (poem, title derived from first line), undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Leges Arcadum, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Drawings of bookplates and crests including Smith, Lloyd P. and Brewster, Benjamin Harris, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Visiting cards (Madame de Klouchine, Mrs. Payson, Cav. Giovannia Battista de Rossi, Mrs. S. Schuster, La Barone A. d'Hangest d'Yvoy, Furst von Bismarck, Pietro Mancion, Dr. Taussig, Madame Calderon de la Barca, Claes Lagergren, and Prof. Domenico Gnoli), undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - "Miss Brewster" article from New York Observer, 1881 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Plan du Palatin, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - "Prayer's for Justice", undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - "Reverend Fabrica di S. Pietro in Vaticano", 1870 May 20 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Reviews of "Compensation" by Brewster (newspaper clippings), undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Reviews of Saint Martin's Summer by Brewster (newspaper clippings), 1866 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Sheet music book: "Duetto-per Soprano e Baritomo", [1856 June 22] (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - "Testament de St. Francois de Sales" (photograph), undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - "Venerdi Santo 11 Aprile 1873" (with envelope) (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Vittorio Amedeo II, Lombardia and Carlo Emanuele III, Sicilia (portrait prints), undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Handmade paper with portrait of Leo XIII and dedication in watermark, undated (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera, undated (Box 20, Folder 36)
- Series VII. Printed publications and newspaper articles
  - "Ball Playing in Rome" by Anne Hampton Brewster (printed in New York Daily Graphic), 1876 August 19 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Ce Qui Est Differe N'est Pas Perov," by Enna Duval (Anne Hampton Brewster) (printed in Evening Bulletin), 1853 April 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "How We Spent Sunday" by Anne Hampton Brewster (printed in Dwight's Journal of Music), 1859 October 8 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "The Home of a Sculptor," by Anne Hampton Brewster (printed in New York World), 1876 December 5 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "Rachel," by Anne Hampton Brewster (printed in Daily Evening Bulletin), circa 1858-1868 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "The Story of Two Women," by Anne Hampton Brewster (printed in New York Daily Graphic), 1876 July 26 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "Vox Humana," by Anne Hampton Brewster (proofs) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (printed in Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, newspaper clipping), 1870 September 9 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (various publications, newspaper clippings), 1870-1888 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (various publication, newspaper clippings), circa 1870 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (mostly from Boston Daily Advertiser, newspaper clippings), circa 1879-1881 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (various publications, newspaper clippings), circa 1880 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Foreign correspondence, letters from Rome (various publications, newspaper clippings), circa 1887 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles by Anne Hampton Brewster, 1869-1882 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles, columns, and printed letters by Anne Hampton Brewster, 1869-1882 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles, columns, and printed letters by Anne Hampton Brewster (some articles tipped in by others), 1869-1883 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles, columns, and printed letters by Anne Hampton Brewster (some articles tipped in by others), 1869-1885 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles, columns, and printed letters by Anne Hampton Brewster (some articles tipped in by others), 1876-1882 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings: Articles, columns, and printed letters by Anne Hampton Brewster (some articles tipped in by others), 1876-1882, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Series VIII. Manuscripts and printed materials of other authors
  - Cowden-Clarke, Mary: "Possessors of Mrs. Cowden Clarke's 'Concordance to Shakespeare'", 1881 January (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - d'Annunzio, Gabriele: "Ballata" (manuscript poem), 1886 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - d'Annunzio, Gabriele: "Tre Odi" (manuscript poem, signed), circa 1886 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - d' Annunzio, Gabriele: "Viviana" (manuscript poem, signed), 1886 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Jackson, Helen Hunt (Untitled manuscript poem?), undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Lanciani, Rodolfo (Eight manuscripts), undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Miller, Cincinnatus Hiner (Joaquin) (Commonplace book fragment), undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Miller, Cincinnatus Hiner (Joaquin): "In Africa" (signed poem), undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Cincinnatus Hiner (Joaquin): "Up the Nile" (signed poem), undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Miller, Cincinnatus Hiner (Joaquin): "Up the Nile" and "In Africa" (copies by Brewster), undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Moulton, Louise Chandler: "For Queen Anne" (manuscript poem), 1876 March 23 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Mulock, Dinah Marie: "Phillip My King" (manuscript poem), undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Parsons, T. W.: "Dante's Purgatorio. Canto Fifteenth" (translation, proof), undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan: "Coals of Fire" (printed poem), 1872 March 8 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan: "The Golden Now" (signed poem), undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Stoddard, Charles Warren: "Roman Receptions at Anne Brewster's Home" (newspaper article), undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Series IX. Correspondence collection
  - Borromeoi, Cardinal to de Medici, Cardinal (copy of a signed letter with envelope), 1869 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Brewster, C. N. to "Sir" (signed letter), 1883 April 5 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Ciccolini, Stefano (two letters), 1873 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Clinton, Dewitt to Ferris, Benjamin (signed letter), 1821 February 13 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Fillmore, Millard to Thomas, Charles F. (signed letter), 1857 May 30 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Fonderie Speciale de Cloches (letter), circa 1870 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Hampton, John T. to Hampton, Mercy (signed letter), 1791 December 28 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Kent, Judge W. to Shufftin, R. L. (signed letter), 1876 July 28 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Lansing, John to Ferris, Benjamin (signed letter), undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Lessoiz, Raul to Stewart, Monsieur (signed letter regarding article on Mariano Fortuny with envelope), undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Linton, E. Lyon to Greenough, Mrs. Richard (signed letter with envelope), 1880 October 15 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Linton, E. Lyon to Story, Evelyn (signed letter), undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Longfellow, Miss. To Read, Thomas and Harriet (letter), 1868 December 23 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Nile, T. to Miller, Cincinnatus Hiner (Joaquin), 1875 July 20 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Offaly, Earl of to Read, Thomas Buchanan and Harriet (letter), 1869 January 14 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Owen, Robert Dale to American Consul (signed letter), 1857 February 15 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Sambon, Giulio (letter), 1892 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Thomas, Ambrose (signed letter), 1880 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Washington, George to Madison, James (copy of a signed letter), 1792 May 20 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Zaid, M. Ali to Layard (copy of a signed letter), undated (Box 23, Folder 36)
- Series X. Newspaper clippings
  - Newspaper clippings about Europe written by Anne Hampton Brewster and others, 1835-1877 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper clippings (French), 1869-1870 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Newspaper clippings of articles by Anne Hampton Brewster and others (mostly about Rome or obituaries), circa 1870 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings of articles about Europe (Italian and English), circa 1870 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings scrapbook, 1872, 1874, 1890, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, mostly about European social life and politics (in English, Italian, and French), 1879-1889 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, foreign correspondence, letters from Rome, 1880-1890 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings about European religious, social, and political affairs (in English, Italian, and French), circa 1880 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings about Europe and obituaries, circa 1890 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding Brewster, Benjamin Harris, 1888 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings of articles written about Rome and Europe by Anne Hampton Brewster and others, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings (English and Italian), undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Series XI. Autograph collection
  - Draft of first section of the Emancipation Proclamation, Lincoln, Abraham, 1862 July 25 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Broadside for the sale of Lincoln's Proclamation, circa 1864 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Certificate for Emancipation Proclamation from Carpenter, T. P., 1864 June 17 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding Lincoln's proclamation from Welling, James C. to Brewster, Anne Hampton, 1864 June 13 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding draft of Emancipation Proclamation from Carpenter, T. P. to Brewster, Anne Hampton, 1865 November 9 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding draft of Emancipation Proclamation from Welling, James C. to Brewster, Anne Hampton, 1868 July 10 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Portrait of Abraham Lincoln by Brady, M. B. (print), undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Lock of hair of Clay, Henry, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Lock of hair of Jackson, Andrew, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)